# Ramin Rezaei

## Front-end Engineer

#### CONTACT

<u>LinkedIn | GitHub | Personal Website</u>

Tehran, Iran | +989136266179 | Ramin.Rezaei77@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a **front-end engineer** with more than **4 years** of experience and a slight acquaintance with back-end development. I am working for **Digikala**, one of the top 3 websites in Iran with about **9 million visits per day**. Digikala is an Iranian online store, similar to Amazon.

#### **EDUCATION**

Islamic Azad University, Najaf Abad Branch - Isfahan Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering Sep 2016 - Sep 2021

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Digikala, Tehran, Iran — Front-end Engineer

Aug 2020 - Present

- Worked in a highly collaborative agile team environment with more than 50 people in different teams.
- Wrote **unit tests** for essential tools and components with **Jest** and **React-Testing-Library**, which reduced reported bugs and errors by 30% in one month.
- Wrote **E2E tests** for the main flows on the site like add-to-cart, and payment with **Cypress**.
- Proposed and innovated a **service** with a new and **fast algorithm** to **track user** behavior with products and banners on the site, which increased the accuracy of the tracked information by 90%.
- Developed a service to **automatically show and hide different features** and sections of the site in **Demo** and **Production** versions, which is applicable in promotions and even for a certain number of users.
- 10% improvement in product page load speed and 30% reduction in API requests by caching data, reusing static information, and removing static requests.
- Increased website view limit by 5x in promotions by rewriting the website with react.

### SnappCarFix, Esfahan, Iran — Front-end Team Lead

May 2019 - Aug 2020

- Implemented 4 PWA and 2 Admin Dashboard Panels.
- The **standard version** (**x**,**y**,**z**) was used for projects, and the automatic update of the **client-side cache**, which in the long run improved the process of product development and updating by 20%.
- **Designed a single layout** for the organization's sales sites. Using this template, you can create a completely new site in just 24 hours.
- Grew the Lottie animations performance by 80% by developing a new wrapper.
- **60% improvement in SwiperJs** performance by writing a wrapper in the project and using it frequently throughout the whole project without loss of performance.
- Made **high-performance and high-use timer parts** for advertisements and discount banners on the site, which improved the site's loading time by 2 seconds.

- Rebuilt the platform from WordPress to React and made more requests with **better UI/UX** and fewer development hassles resulting in a **90% improvement in user experience**.
- I managed 10 people, working on 3 individual project types with the same technology for different parts of the company.

#### **Self-Employed,** Esfahan, Iran — *Freelance*

Jan 2019 - May 2019

- Designed and implemented **2 web platforms** with **React, PWA, and Django** for club management and product sales, which have been running for more than 3 years.
- Created more than 12 landing pages for events and promotions.

#### **SKILLS**

- → Front-end: **JavaScript**, **ReactJS**, Html, CSS, SASS, LESS, Tailwind, NextJs, TypeScript, StoryBook, Jest, Cypress, A/B testing, JQuery, and familiar with VueJs.
- → Back-end: **Python** (Django), SQL, MySQL, Rest API, Docker.
- → Others: Git, Linux OS, Scrum, Trunk-based Development (TBD), GitFlow.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Persian - Native

English - General level

Visit my **LinkedIn** to read what others have to say about me.